Tim Rose

A full-stack web developer with a passion for solving problems. Recently completed the Coding Bootcamp through the University of Sydney. High-level analytical and problem-solving abilities have been honed over thirteen years working in the IT industry as a systems engineer. Many years of customer service experience have resulted in proven, highly developed interpersonal and communication skills, and I have been awarded for outstanding service delivery.

Key Strengths

- Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+.
- Frameworks: React, jQuery, Bootstrap.
- Back end: Node, Express, MongoDB, MySQL
- Proven analytical and problem-solving skills.
- Many years of customer service experience in a number of different fields.
- High-level communication and interpersonal skills.

Projects

CommunityConnect

https://github.com/rorydavidtanner/CommunityConnect

- https://communityconnect-1.herokuapp.com/
- An online app connecting people who need help with volunteers in their community.
- Role: database, routing and front-end JavaScript
- Tech: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Bootstrap

Employee Directory

https://github.com/timsilby/TS-19-Employee-Directory/https://timsilby.github.io/TS-19-Employee-Directory/

- A React application for viewing employee information.
- · Role: sole author
- Tech: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Node, React, Bootstrap

Informed Traveller

https://github.com/Epanastatis2020/Informed-Travel-App https://epanastatis2020.github.io/Informed-Travel-App/

- A web app which shows news and weather relevant to a specific location.
- · Role: JavaScript, front-end styling
- Tech: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap

Professional Experience

Apples on Ainsworth Café

September 2019 - present

Barista

- Work as part of a small, close-knit team to provide an exceptional customer experience.
- Build relationships with a strong regular client base.
- · Trained and supervised several junior staff
- · Manage café when owner is away.

Café Auchenflower/The Green Owl

February 2017 - April 2019

Barista/Bartender

- Used extensive customer service and interpersonal skills to provide an exceptional customer experience.
- Built and maintained strong relationships with regular clients.

Datacom Systems

April 2011 - January 2017

IT Systems Engineer

- Held a senior position in a high-performing team that was responsible for delivering services to a number of large clients across the country.
- Assisted with the implementation and delivery of a new hosted email offering including formulation of operational procedures.
- Developed strong relationships with external clients to enable more comprehensive and effective service delivery.
- Received an Employee of the Quarter award for Service Delivery.

Queensland Health

February 2008 - March 2011

IT Systems Engineer (Contract)

- Held a position as acting team leader responsible for a team of four technical staff.
- Utilised high-level technical and communication skills (written and verbal) to help deliver a major enterprise-wide project.
- Followed standardised practices and procedures to resolve incident and problem tickets within agreed timeframes.

Education

Certificates

- Full Stack Web Development University of Sydney (February 2021).
- ITIL v3 Foundation (August 2014)
- VMware Certified Professional 5 DCV (March 2014)
- MCITP Windows Server 2008 Enterprise Administrator (August 2012)
- MCTS Windows Server 2008 R2, Server Virtualization (May 2012)

Other

• Diploma of Systems Technology (Spherion Education, 2003)